By now you've seen most of the key
building blocks of our RNN.
But there are just two more ideas that
let you build much more powerful models.
One is bidirectional RNN,
which lets
you at the point in time to take information from both
earlier and later
in the sequence. So talk about that in this video.
And the second is deep RNN,
which you see in the next video.
So that starts with bidirectional RNN.
So to motivate bidirectional RNN, let's
look at this network which you've seen
a few times before in the context
of named entity recognition.
And one of the problems
of this network is that,
to figure out whether the third word
Teddy is a part of a person's name,
it's not enough to just look at
the first part of the sentence.
So to tell if y3 should be 01,
you need more information than
just the first few words.
Because the first three words doesn't tell
you if they're talking about Teddy
bears, or talk about the former US President,
Teddy Roosevelt.
So this is a unidirectional or
four directional only RNN.
And this comment I just made
is true whether these cells
are standard RNN blocks, or
whether there are
GRU units, or whether they're LSTM blocks, right?
But all these blocks are in a forward only direction
What a bidirection RNN does or a BRNN is fix this issue
A birectional RNN works as follows.  I'm going to simplify to use a simplified
four input sentence
So we have four inputs, X1 through X4.
So this network's hidden there will
have a forward recurring components.
So I'm going to call this a1,
a2, a3, and a4.
And I'm going to draw a right arrow over
that to the notices the four
recurrent component.
And so w connected as follows.
And so each of these four recurrent
units influence the current X.
And then on feeds in,
To help predict y hat 1, y hat 2,
y hat 3, and y hat 4.
So far I haven't done anything, right?
Basically, we draw on the RNN
from the previous slide, but
with the arrows place in
slightly funny positions.
But I drew the arrows in these
slightly funny positions because what
we're going to do is add
a backward recurrent there.
That would have a1, left arrow to denote
this is a backward connection,
and then a2 backwards,
a3 backwards, and a4 backwards.
So the left arrow denotes it
is a backward connection.
And so we're then going to connect
the network up as follows.
And these a backward
connections will be connected
to each other, going backwards in time.
So notice that this network
defines a cyclic draft.
And so, given an input sequence X1 to X4,
the four sequence we first compute a for
(1), then use that to compute a for
(2), then a for (3), then a for (4).
Whereas the backward sequence will
start by computing a backward four and
then go back and compute a backward three.
And notice your computing
network activations.
This is not background, this is for
a problem but the for profit goals has
partially but the forward problem has part
of the complication going from left to
right and positive competition going
from right to left in this diagram.
But I havent computed a backward three.
You can then use those activations
completely backward two, and
then a backward one.
And then finally, you haven't computed
all your hidden their activations.
You can then make your predictions.
And so for example,
to make the predictions
your network would have
something like y hat
at time T is an activation
function apply to WY
with both the forward
activation at time T.
And the backward activation
at time T being fed in,
to make that prediction at time T.
So if you look at the prediction
at times set 3 for example,
then information from X1 can
flow through here for one to for
2, that also takes an information here,
to for 3, so y had three.
So information from X1, X2,
X3 are all taking account
with information from X4 can
flow through a backward four
to a backward three 2y.
So this allows the production and
tie three to take his input
both information from the past,
as well as information from the present,
which goes into both the forward and
backward things at this step,
as well as information from the future.
So in particular, given a phrase like
he said Teddy Roosevelt...to predict
whether Teddy was part of a person's name.
You give to take into account information
from the past and from the future.
So this is the bidirectional
recurrent neural network.
And these blocks here can be not
just the standard RNN block,
but they can also be GRU blocks,
or LSTM blocks.
In fact, for a lot of NLP problems,
for a lot of text or
natural language processing problems,
a bidirectional RNN with a LSTM
appears to be commonly used.
So, if you have an NLP problem,
and you have a complete sentence,
you're trying to label things in the
sentence, a bidirectional RNN with LSTM
blocks before then backward would be
a pretty reasonable first thing to try.
So that's it for the bidirectional RNN.
And this is a modification they can
make to the basic RNN architecture,
or the GRU, or the LSTM.
And by making this change, you can have
a model that uses RNN, or GRU, LSTM,
and is able to make predictions anywhere
even in the middle of the sequence, but
take into account information
potentially from the entire sequence.
The disadvantage of
the bidirectional RNN is that,
you do need the entire sequence of data
before you can make predictions anywhere.
So, for example, if you're building
a speech recognition system then BRNN will
let you take into account
the entire speech other friends.
But if you use this
straightforward implementation,
you need to wait for the person to stop
talking to get the entire utterance before
you can actually process it, and
make a speech recognition prediction.
So the real time speech
recognition applications,
there is somewhat more complex models as
well rather than just using the standard
by the rational RNN as you're seeing here.
But for a lot of natural language
processing applications where you can get
the entire sentence all at the same time,
the standard BRN and
algorithm is actually very effective.
So that's it for BRNN in the Nixon
final video for this week.
Let's talk about how to take all
of these ideas RNN, LSTM, GRUz,
and bidirectional versions, and
construct deep versions of them.